Are you a doctor?
Yes. Yes.
He's an actor.
Oh, an actor.
We're very popular with actors.
Have I, uh, seen you in anything?
Let's see. I did Hamlet a
while back, didn't I, Liz?
And then we did, the, uh,
The Sandpiper.
He's joking.
He was in Luther
and Nobody Loves an Albatross
and a lot of television
plays and commercials.
Well, that's where the money
is, isn't it? Commercials.
And the artistic thrills, too.
7, Diego.
Originally, the smallest
apartment was a 9.
They've been broken up into
four, fives, and sixes.
Now, 7-E is a four,
originally the back part of a 10.
It has the original dining
room for its living room,
another bedroom for the bedroom,
and two servants' rooms
thrown together
for a dining room or a second bedroom.
Do you have children?
Uh, we plan to.
We must oil that gate,
Diego.
This way, please.
The previous tenant, Mrs. Gardenia,
passed away just a few days ago,
So nothing has been moved yet.
Her son asked me to say that
some of the furniture
could be picked up practically
for the asking.
Did she die in the apartment?
Not that it makes any difference.
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
In a hospital.
She'd been in a coma for weeks.
After you, please.
Thank you.
She was very old
and passed away without ever waking.
I'd be grateful to go that way
myself when the time comes.
Oh, no, no, no, not
in the apartment, no.
She was chipper right to the end,
been one of the first women
lawyers in New York state.
Did a little gardening on
the side, too.
She was quite a woman.
Oh, closet.
Oh, plenty of closets.
Oh, nice view of the park.
Oh, very nice view.
Yeah.
Now, this room, for instance,
it would make a lovely nursery.
Yes. Yellow and white wallpaper
would brighten it tremendously.
What are all these things here?
Herbs, mostly.
A nice large bathroom.
Mmm. Mint, basil.
Yeah.
No marijuana?
Come on.
The, uh, master bedroom.
Oh, yes.
Here we are, back at the hallway again.
There.
Oh.
Oh, Guy!
Yeah.
Ohh!
The fireplace works,
of course.
Great.
Ohl
Oh, it's a wonderful apartment.
I love it!
See what she's trying to do?
She's trying to get you
to lower the rent, see?
Yes.
Well, we'd raise it if we were allowed.
Apartments with this kind of charm--
Why, that's odd.
There's a closet behind that secretary.
I'm su--
I'm sure there is.
Yeah. Oh, I think you're right.
She moved it.
It used to be there.
Ohh! Give me a hand, will you?
I see now why she went into a coma.
Ha, ha, hal
She couldn't have lifted it by herself.
She was 89.
Should we open it?
Maybe her son should.
I'm authorized to show the apartment.
Well!
Whatever she locked in
got out.
Well, perhaps she didn't
need five closets.
Why would she cover up her vacuum
cleaner and her towels?
I don't suppose we'll ever know.
Maybe she was becoming senile after all.
Is there anything else?
Yes, please. What about
the laundry facilities?
It's bigger than the other one.
Yeah. It's more expensive,
too, you know?
It's better located.
Yeah, well, God knows,
I could walk to all the
theaters from here.
Oh, Guy, let's take it, please?
That living room could be--
Oh, please, let's take it.
Okay, darling, we get out
of the other lease, okay.
I was tempted to write the management
that you were drug addicts
and litterbugs.
Instead, I decided to lie
and tell them you were
wonderful tenants.
Oh, you're great, Hutch.
Wish I could talk you out of it, though.
He's pulling your leg, Ro honey.
Indeed I'm not.
Now, that looks great.
That is--
Are you aware that the Bramford
had rather an unpleasant reputation
around the turn of the century?
It's where the Trench sisters
conducted their little
dietary experiments
and Keith Kennedy held his parties.
Adrian Marcato lived there, too.
So did Pearl Ames.
Who were the Trench sisters?
Who was Adrian Marcato?
The Trench sisters were two
proper Victorian ladies.
They cooked and ate several young
children, including a niece.
Oh, lovely.
Adrian Marcato practiced witchcraft.
He made quite a splash in the nineties
by announcing that he'd conjured
up the living devil.
Apparently, people believed him,
so they attacked and nearly killed him
in the lobby of the Bramford.
You're joking.
Later, the Keith Kennedy business began,
and by the twenties, the
house was half empty.
I knew about Keith Kennedy.
I didn't know that Marcato
lived there.
And those sisters.
World War ll filled the house up again.
Terrific.
What? The house?
The lamb.
Oh.
They called it Black Bramford.
But, Hutch, awful things happen
in every apartment house.
Ah, but this house has a high incidence
of unpleasant happenings.
In '59, a dead infant was found,
wrapped in newspaper in the basement.
Mmm! You really rouse my appetite.
Have some more wine.
Roman!
Bring me in some root beer
when you come!
Hey, these are shelves.
Hey...
let's make love.
Shh!
I think I hear the Trench
sisters chewing.
Ohl
Straight up to the left.
Here in Daytona, Florida,
it's the 250-cc 100-mile classic
with Yamaha leading the
pack on the final lap...
and winning it, as Yamaha takes
7 of the top 10 places.
It's the third straight year
for Yamaha, a clean sweep.
Yamaha is race bred from champions,
and, as you can see,
we have a model for
every kind of riding.
You know, you really should discover
the swingin' world of Yamaha.
Why don't you get on, have a ride?
Come on. Get on.
Okay, come on.
Let's go.
Look.
It's great.
I'm sorry. I thought you were
Victoria Vetri, the actress.
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
A lot of people think I'm Victoria.
I don't see any resemblance.
Do you know her?
No.
My name's Terry Gionoffrio.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Rosemary Woodhouse.
Uh, we-- We're new tenants here.
I'm staying with the Castevets,
seventh floor.
I'm their guest, sort of, since June.
Our apartment used to be
the back part of yours.
Oh, for goodness sakes.
You took the old lady's
apartment. Mrs., uh--
Yeah, um, Miss, uh...
Gard-- Gardenia.
Gardenia. Yeah.
She was a good friend of the Castevets.
She used to grow all kinds of herbs
and things for her to cook with.
I saw those plants.
Yeah. Well, now, she
grows her own things.
Excuse me a moment.
I have to put the softener in.
What does your husband do?
He's an actor.
No kidding?
What's his name?
Guy Woodhouse.
He was in Luther and Nobody
Loves an Albatross,
and he does a lot of
television and radio.
Gee, I watch TV all day long.
I'll bet I've seen him.
Wow!
Ooh!
I hate this basement.
Yeah, me, too.
It gives me the creeps.
Listen, why don't we come
down here together regular
and do our laundry?
Okay, that would be great.
I have a good luck charm.
It might work for both of us.
Oh, that's beautiful.
Isn't it?
Mmm-hmm!
Mrs. Castevet gave it to me.
It's good luck.
Anyway, it's supposed to be.
It's got some stuff inside.
Ha, ha, hal
I'm not mad about the smell either.
I hope it works.
It's a beautiful charm, though.
I've never seen anything like it.
European.
The Castevets are the most wonderful
people in the world, bar none.
You know, they picked me up
off the sidewalk, literally?
You were sick?
I was starving and on dope
and doing a lot of other things.
They're childless, though.
I'm like the daughter they never had.
At first, I thought they wanted
me for some kind of sex thing,
but they've turned out to
be like real grandparents.
It's nice to know there
are people like that
when you hear so much about apathy
and people who are afraid
of getting involved.
I'd be dead now if it wasn't for them.
That's an absolute fact,
dead or in jail.
You don't have any family
that could have helped you?
A brother in the navy.
Why, it's impossible to be 100% sure!
If you want my opinion, we
shouldn't tell her at all!
That's my opinion!
That must be the partition.
That's the back part of the original
10 with a dining room,
and there's--
there's a closet over here,
and then there's a closet over here.
Stay back, huh, lady?
Get back now, will you, please?
Get back. There's nothing to see.
Get back, will you, please?
Jesus.
Get back!
We know her.
What's her name?
Terry.
Terry what?
Ro?
What was her name again?
Terry what?
uh...
I don't remember.
An Italian name.
She was staying with some
people named Castevet,
7-E.
Yeah. We got that already.
Short and sweet.
She stuck it to the windowsill
with a Band-Aid. Come on.
Get back.
Theresa Gionoffrio.
Move on!
You knew her?
Only slightly.
Come on, Ro baby.
Let's go.
Oh! Here they come.
You folks the Castevets
on the seventh floor?
We are.
You have a young woman
named Theresa Gionoffrio
living with you?
We do. What's wrong?
Has there been an accident?
You'd better brace yourself
for some bad news.
She's dead.
Jumped out of the window.
That's not possible!
That's a mistake!
Artie, you want to let these
folks take a look, please?
I knew this would happen.
She got deeply depressed
every three weeks or so.
I told my wife about it,
but she pooh-poohed me.
Well, that-- that doesn't
mean she killed herself.
She was a very happy girl
with no reason for self-destruction.
She must have been cleaning
the windows or something.
She wasn't cleaning windows at midnight.
Why not? Maybe she was!
Is that her handwriting?
Yeah.
Definitely.
Absolutely.
Thank you.
I'll see this gets back to
you when we're done with it.
I don't believe it.
I just don't believe it.
She was so happy.
Who's the next of kin?
She's all alone.
She didn't have anybody,
only us.
Didn't she have a brother?
Did she?
She said she did.
In the navy.
News to me.
Do you know where he's stationed?
No, I don't.
She mentioned him to me
in the laundry room.
I'm Rosemary Woodhouse.
Uh, we're in, uh, 7-E.
I feel just the way you
do, Mrs. Castevet.
She seemed so happy and full of--
She said wonderful things
about you and your husband,
how grateful she was.
Thank you.
You know anything else
about this brother
except he's in the navy?
No, I don't.
It should be easy
to find him.
Okay.
I'm so stunned.
I'm so sorry.
It's such a pity.
Well, thank you.
Sometimes I wonder how come you're
the leader of anything.
Please don't tell me
what Laura-Louise said
because I'm not interested.
If you'd listened to me,
we wouldn't have had to do this!
We'd have been all set to go now
instead of having to start
all over from scratch!
I told you not to tell her in advance!
I told you she wouldn't be open-minded!
I told Sister Veronica
about the windows,
and she withdrew the school
from the competition.
Otherwise, we would--
Hello. How are you?
Fine. May I come in a minute?
Yes, of course. Please do.
I just come over to thank you
for saying those nice things
to us the other night.
Oh, no, please.
There's--
Poor Terry.
We thought maybe we'd
failed her some way,
although her note made it
crystal clear we hadn't.
You'll never know how helpful it was
in such a shock moment.
So I do thank you.
Roman does, too.
Roman's my hubby.
You're welcome.
I'm glad I could help.
Yeah. Well, she was cremated yesterday.
Now we got to forget and go on.
It won't be easy.
We don't have any children of our own.
You have any?
No, we don't.
Oh, well, there you have it.
Ohh! Oh,
that's a nice--
Look how you put the table!
Now, isn't that interesting?
I saw it in a magazine.
Oh, my. Nice paint job.
I know.
Ahh... well.
That's nice.
What is that?
That's the TV room?
Yeah, well, only temporarily.
It's going to be a nursery.
Oh, you're pregnant?
No, not yet.
I hope to be as soon as we're settled.
Wonderful. Well, you're
young and healthy.
You ought to have lots of children.
We plan to have three.
I'm dying to see what you
did to this apartment.
The woman who had it before
was a dear friend of mine.
I know.
Terry told me.
Oh, did she?
You two had some long talks
together in the laundry room.
Only one.
Oh! Oh, my goodness!
Ah, ha, ha! It looks so much brighter.
What do you pay for a chair like that?
Uh, oh...
um, I'm not sure, really.
I think about $200.
Hmm.
What does your hubby do?
He's an actor.
I knew it! I said it to Roman yesterday.
He's so good-looking.
What movies was he in?
No movies.
He was in two plays called Luther
and Nobody Loves an Albatross
and a lot of television and radio.
Listen, Rosemary...
I got a 2-inch thick sirloin steak
sitting defrosting right this minute.
Why don't you and Guy come over,
have supper with us tonight?
What do you say?
Oh, no. We couldn't.
Why not?
No, really, that's very kind of you.
Listen--
It would be a real help to us. Oh--
First night we'll be alone since--
Oh, are you sure it wouldn't
be too much trouble for you?
Oh, honey, if it was trouble,
I wouldn't ask you.
All right.
You go ahead and count on us.
I'll have to check with Guy,
though.
Listen, you tell him I won't
take no for an answer!
Oh! Here's your mail!
Oh! Ads!
Thank you.
Yoo-hoo!
Hey.
Mmm!
Donald Baumgart got that part.
It's a bad play anyway.
Yeah. Even if it folds out of town,
it's the kind of part that gets noticed.
Mrs. Castevet was here
to thank me for what I said about Terry.
She is the nosiest person
I've ever seen.
You know she actually asked
the prices of things?
No kidding.
She invited us to have dinner
with them tonight.
I told her I'd have to check with you,
but that it would probably be okay.
Oh, Jesus! We don't have
to do that, do we, honey?
I think they're lonely.
We get friendly with an
old couple like that,
and we'll never get rid of them.
They're right across the wall.
I told her she could count on us.
You don't have to sulk about it.
I'm not sulking.
I see exactly what you mean.
Hell, we'll go.
No, no. What for?
We'll go!
No. We don't have to
if you don't want to.
That sounds so phony, but I
really mean it, really, I do.
Be my good deed for the day.
Okay, but only if you want to.
We'll make it clear that it's
just for this one night
and not the beginning
of anything, right?
Oh! Perfect timing!
Come oniin.
Roman's fixing us some vodka blushes.
My, I'm glad you could come, Guy.
I'm fixing to tell everybody
that I knew you when.
Look, dinner isn't ready just yet,
but sit down there anywhere.
Take a seat on the couch.
You'll find yourself very comfortable.
I seem to have overfilled the glasses.
No, no, no.
Don't get up.
Generally, I pour these out precisely
as a bartender, don't I, Minnie?
Just watch the carpet.
But this evening I made
a little too much,
and rather I'm afr--
Oh, there we are.
No, no, no.
Sit down, please.
Now, Mrs. Woodhouse--
Thank you.
Uh, Mr. Woodhouse,
uh, vodka blush?
Yes, thanks.
Have you ever tasted one?
No, no.
I haven't.
It looks delicious.
Minnie. They're very
popular in Australia.
Now, to our guests--
Welcome to our home.
Hear, hear.
Cheers.
Mmm.
The carpet.
Oh, dear.
Brand-new carpet.
This man is so clumsy!
Do you come from Australia?
Oh, no, no. I'm from right
here in New York City.
I've been there, though.
I've been everywhere, literally.
You name a place, and I've been there.
Go ahead. Name a place.
Fairbanks, Alaska!
I've been there, been all over Alaska--
Yes-- Fairbanks, Juneau, Anchorage,
Nome, Sitka, Seward.
I spent four months there in '38--
Where are you folks from?
Well--
Well, I--
I'm from Omaha.
Guy's from Baltimore.
Omaha's a good city.
Baltimore is, too.
Do you travel for business?
Well, business and pleasure both.
I'm 79, and I've been going one
place or another since I was 10.
You name a place, I've been there.
Ah! Steak's ready.
Don't rush your drinks, now.
Roman, take your pill!
No pope ever visits a city
where the newspapers are on strike.
I heard he's going to postpone
and wait till it's over.
Well, that's show biz.
That's exactly what it is.
All the costumes are rituals,
all religions.
Oh, I think we're offending Rosemary.
No, no.
No, you're not religious,
my dear, are you?
Well, I was brought up a Catholic.
Now I don't know.
You looked uncomfortable.
Well, he is the pope.
Now, you don't need to
have respect for him
because he pretends that he's holy.
Now, that's a good point.
When I think what they spend
on robes and jewels!
A good picture of the hypocrisy
behind organized religion
was given, I thought, in Luther.
Did you ever get to play
that leading part, Guy?
Me? No.
Weren't you Albert Finney's understudy?
No.
Well, that's strange.
I remember being struck
by a gesture you made
and checking in the program
to see who you were.
Thank you.
Um, what gesture was that?
Well, I'm not sure now.
It was a reaction--
Oh, I did a thing with my arms
when Luther was having a fit.
It was a kind of involuntary reach.
That's it! That's it.
It had a wonderful authenticity to it.
Oh, come on.
No, no.
I mean it.
My father was a theatrical producer,
and my early years were
spent in the company
of Mrs. Fiske, Forbes-Robertson,
Modjeska.
Guy?
Oh, yes, please.
You have a most interesting
inner quality, Guy.
It appears in your television work, too.
It should take you a long way, indeed,
provided, of course, that you
get those initial breaks.
Are you preparing for a show now?
Um, well, I'm up for a couple parts.
Well, I can't believe that
you won't get them.
Well, I can.
I'd like to have a spice garden someday.
I guess I'm a country girl at heart.
You come from a big family?
Mm-hmm.
Three brothers and two sisters.
Your sisters married?
Mm-hmm.
They have children?
One has two, the other has four.
There's a chance you'll have
lots of children, too.
We're fertile, all right.
I've got 16 nieces and nephews.
Oh, my goodness!
Would you like me to wash, and
you can wipe for a while?
Oh, no.
That's fine, dear.
Now, Roman, will you stop
bending Guy's ears
with your Modjeska stories?
He's only listening 'cause he's polite.
No, no, no, no.
It's very interesting, Mrs. Castevet.
Minnie!
I'm Minnie.
He's Roman, okay?
Okay?
Okay.
Okay!
Terrific.
Just terrific.
Good-bye, darling.
Good-bye.
Thank you for having us.
Yeah, it was lovely.
Oh, bless you.
Minnie!
Minnie, ya good kid, ya.
Ooh!
About that steak, huh?
Oh, my God!
And the cake.
How did you eat two pieces?
It was weird.
Out of politeness.
That's how I ate two pieces.
Ha, ha, hal
Only three dinner plates that matched.
Shh!
And all that beautiful,
beautiful silver.
We'll be nice.
Maybe they'll will it to us.
Ohl
Yeah.
Guess what they have in their bathroom.
A bidet.
Jokes for the John.
No.
A book on a hook right
next to the toilet.
Roman's stories are pretty
damned interesting, though.
Yeah?
Never even heard of Forbes-Robertson
before.
I'm going to go over there again
tomorrow night and hear some more.
You are?
Yeah. He asked me.
Here. Do this damn thing
for me, will you?
I thought we were going to do something
with Joan and Dick Jellico.
Was that definite?
Well, it wasn't definite.
We'll see them next week.
You don't have to come along
if you don't want to.
You can stay here.
Yeah, I think I will stay here.
He knew Henry Irving, too.
I mean, really interesting, you know?
Why did they take their pictures down?
What do you mean?
Their pictures.
They took them down.
The hooks in the wall and clean spaces
and the one picture that
is there doesn't fit.
I didn't notice that.
Hi, dear. We're not bothering
you, are we?
This is my dear friend
Laura-Louise McBurney,
lives up on 12.
Laura-Louise, this is
Guy's wife, Rosemary.
Hello, Rosemary.
Welcome to the Bram!
Laura-Louise just met Guy.
She wanted to meet you, too.
Could we come in?
Uh, of course.
Please do.
There you are.
Go ahead.
Oh, look what you got.
There's a light.
Oh, gosh!
Isn't that beautiful!
It came this morning.
Are you all right, dear?
You look worn.
Oh, no. I'm fine.
It's the first day of my period.
And you're up and around?
On my first day, I experienced
such pain,
I couldn't move, eat, or anything.
Dan used to give me gin through
a straw to kill the pain.
Girls today take things much
more in their stride.
They're much healthier than we were,
Thanks to vitamins, better medical care.
What are those things over
there, seat covers?
Um, cushions for the window seats.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, before I forget.
This is for you from Roman and me.
For me?
It's just a little present
is all. For moving in.
There's no reason--
It's real old.
It's over 300 years.
It's lovely.
Yeah. The green inside
is called tannis root.
That's for good luck.
It's lovely, but I--
I can't accept it.
You already have.
Put it on.
Yeah.
Ah, you'll get used to the
smell before you know it.
Yeah, go on.
Ohh, yes.
Were his stories as interesting
as last night?
Yes. Did you have a good time?
All right.
I got a present.
It was Terry's.
No kidding?
Kind of pretty, though.
Aren't you going to wear it?
Mm-mmm.
It smells.
There's stuff in it called tannis root
from her greenhouse.
Not too bad, though.
Ha, ha, ha.
Tannis, anyone?
Well, if you took it,
you ought to wear it.
Hello.
Yes.
This is he.
Oh, God, no.
Oh, the poor guy.
And, uh...
they don't have any idea
what's causing it?
Oh, my God.
That's awful.
That's just awful.
Yes, I would.
I mean, yes, I am.
I hate to get it that way, but--
Well, you'd have to speak to my agent
about that end of it.
Alan Stone.
I'm sure there won't be
any problem, Mr. Weiss,
not as far as we're concerned.
Thank you, Mr. Weiss.
Guy?
What is it?
Donald Baumgart--
He's gone blind.
He woke up yesterday, and he can't see.
Oh, no.
Oh, I've got the part.
It's a hell of a way to get it.
Listen, uh,
I have to get out and walk around.
I understand.
Go ahead.
Baumgart--
Donald Baumgart.
It's a fascinating part.
He'll really be noticed this time.
He also has an offer for a lead
in a television series, Miami
Beach.
He's suddenly very hot.
Mm-hmm. I understand why
you're so overjoyed.
Well, it's a difficult
period in his life.
A challenge.
I see.
You know how actors are.
They're all a bit self-centered.
I'll bet even Laurence Olivier
is vain and self-centered.
It's a difficult part.
He's got to work with crutches,
and, naturally, he's preoccupied.
And he--
Well, preoccupied.
I see you had another suicide
up there at happy house.
Oh, didn't I tell you?
No, you didn't.
It was that girl I told you about,
the drug-addict who was rehabilitated
by this old couple, the Castevets.
I'm sure I told you that.
They didn't rehabilitate her
very successfully, it seems.
I've been a creep.
It's from worrying if Baumgart
would regain his sight,
rat that I am.
Oh, it's natural.
You're bound to feel two ways about it.
Even if I'm Mr. Yamaha
for the rest of my days,
I'm going to stop giving you
the short end of the stick.
You haven't been.
Yes, I have.
I've been tearing my hair
out over my career.
Let's have a baby.
All right?
Let's have three babies,
one at a time, all right?
A baby. You know.
Mama, Dada, poo-poo.
You know?
You mean it?
Sure, I mean it.
I mean, I even figured out
the right time to start,
look.
You mean it, really?
No, I'm kidding.
Sure, I mean it.
Oh, Ro, honey, for God's
sake, don't cry.
I won't. I won't.
Ha, ha, ha.
Here goes nothing.
The paint!
Good grief.
Nobody, but nobody has a fire tonight.
Isn't it gorgeous?
I hope we have the coldest winter ever.
Oh, shit!
Hi, Guy!
How are ya?
No, don't let her in.
Not tonight.
Oh, that's very kind of you.
Oh, are you sure
you don't want to come in?
No! I don't want to bother you.
Good.
Who says there's nothing to E.S.P.?
Madame and monsieur shall have
ze dessert after all!
Mousse au chocolat.
Or as Minnie calls it--
chocolate mouse.
I was afraid she'd stay all evening.
She just wanted us to try it.
Seein' it's one of her specialities.
It was sweet of her, really.
We shouldn't make fun of her.
Yeah, you're right, you're
right, you're right.
Mmm! It's good.
Has an undertaste.
A chalky undertaste.
I don't get it.
That's silly, honey.
There is no undertaste.
There is.
Come on. The old bat slaved all day.
Now eat it.
I don't like it.
It's delicious.
Here.
You can have mine.
All right. Don't eat it.
There's always something wrong.
Oh, if it's going to turn
into a big thing--
Look, if you really can't stand
it, just don't eat it.
Mmm! It's delicious!
No undertaste at all.
Would you turn the record over, please?
There, Daddy, do I get a gold star?
You get two of them.
I'm sorry if I was stuffy.
You were.
...Is making a full circle
of the ball park...
It's the pope at Yankee Stadium!
...to his specially built
canopy at second base.
Christ, what a mob!
Listen to that crowd roar.
Everywhere the pope has been today,
he's received this type of reception.
As one man put it this afternoon,
"Perhaps we are being undignified,
but this is a special day."
And a special day it has been.
That's a great spot for
my Yamaha commercial.
Ha, ha, hal
I'd like to give you a brief summary
of today's historic happenings.
Pope Paul VI arrived at 9:27 A.M...
What is it?
Dizzy.
Hey.
No wonder.
All that booze.
Ha, ha.
You didn't eat anything all
day before dinner, huh?
Hey.
Nice.
Sleep is what you need.
A good night's sleep.
We have to make a baby.
Oh, we'll--
we'll do it.
Tomorrow.
There's plenty of time.
Just a nap.
Why are you taking them off?
To make you more comfortable.
I am more comfortable.
Sleep, Ro.
Isn't Hutch coming with us?
Catholics only,
I wish we weren't bound
by these prejudices,
but, unfortunately--
Easy, easy.
You got her too high.
Typhoon!
It killed 55 people in London,
and it's heading this way!
You better go down below, miss.
She's awake.
She sees.
She don't see.
As long as she ate the mouse,
she can't see nor hear.
She's like dead.
Now sing.
I'm sorry to hear
you aren't feeling well.
It's only the mouse bite.
You'd better have your legs tied down
in case of convulsions.
Yes, I suppose so.
There's always a chance it was rabid.
If the music bothers you,
let me know, and I'll have
it stopped.
Oh, no, no, no.
Please don't change the
program on my account.
Try to sleep.
We'll be waiting up on deck.
This is no dream!
This is really happening!
They tell me you have
been bitten by a mouse.
Yes. That's why I couldn't
come to see you.
That's all right.
We wouldn't want you to
jeopardize your health.
Am I forgiven, Father?
Oh, absolutely.
Hey, it's after 9:00.
Uhm.
Five minutes.
I have to be at Alan's at 10:00.
Eat out.
Like hell I will.
What time is it?
It's 10 after 9:00.
What time did I go to sleep?
You didn't go to sleep.
You passed out.
From now on you get cocktails or wine,
not cocktails and
wine, hmm?
The dreams I had.
Don't yell.
I already filed them down.
I didn't want to miss baby night.
A couple of my nails were ragged.
You-- While I was out?
And it was kind of fun, in
a "necrophile sort of way.
I dreamed someone was raping me.
I don't know, someone inhuman.
Thanks a lot!
What's the matter?
Nothing.
I didn't want to miss the night.
We could've done it this
morning or tonight.
Last night wasn't the only split second.
I was a little bit loaded
myself, you know?
Oh! Hello there.
Did ya like it?
Oh, yes.
I think I put a little too
much cream de cocoa in it.
No, no.
It was delicious.
You'll have to give me the recipe.
Yeah, love to.
Oh, listen, you going shopping?
Do me a teeny favor, will ya?
Get me six eggs, a small instant Sanka.
I'll pay you later.
Right.
Bye-bye.
Ahh.
Don't you think we ought
to talk about it?
About what?
The way you haven't been looking at me.
What are you talking about?
I've been looking at you.
You haven't.
Why, sure, I have.
Now, what is it?
What's the matter?
Nothing. Never mind.
No, no.
Don't say that.
What is it?
Nothing.
Look, honey, I--
I know I've been preoccupied
with the part and all,
but it is important.
That doesn't mean I don't love you.
It was due on Friday.
It was?
Mm-hmm.
It'll probably come tonight or tomorrow.
Wanna bet?
Yeah.
A quarter.
Okay.
You're going to lose.
Shut up, will you?
You're getting me all jumpy.
It's only been two days.
When will I know?
I'll call you just as soon
as I get the results.
I like to do a general examination
just to know something more.
It was Elise Dunstan who recommended
you to me, Doctor.
Oh, yes.
How is she?
She's fine.
And the boys are great.
Did you deliver them?
No, just the last.
Universal hemoglobin.
Yes, Doctor.
We went to see The Fantasticks.
Did you?
Mmm.
Did you enjoy it?
Yeah.
Good.
Hello?
Mrs. Woodhouse?
Dr. Hill?
Congratulations.
Really?
Really.
Are you there?
Uh, yes, um, what happens now?
You come see me next month.
You get those natalin pills.
One a day.
I'll mail you forms for the hospital.
Uh, when will it be?
It works out to be June 28th.
That sounds so far away.
Itis.
One more thing, Mrs. Woodhouse,
we'd like another blood sample.
Oh, yes, of course.
What for?
The nurse didn't take enough,
so would you drop by and see her?
But I am pregnant, aren't I?
Oh, yes, it's just for blood samp--
Blood sugar and so forth.
But you're pregnant.
Don't worry.
All right.
Well, I'll come in on Monday.
Don't forget the pills.
No, I won't.
Good-bye, Mrs. Woodhouse.
Good-bye, Dr. Hill.
Blood sugar?
What's that?
Oh! That's great.
That's just great.
Father.
Mother.
Heh, heh.
Guy, Guy, listen.
Let's, uh, make this
a new beginning, okay?
A new openness in talking to each other,
because we haven't been open.
That's true.
I've been so goddamned self-centered.
That's what the whole trouble is.
You know I love you, don't you, Ro?
I do.
I swear to God
I'm going to be as open and--
It's my fault as much as yours.
No, bull, it's mine.
Now you bear with me.
I'm gonna try and do better, you hear?
Oh, Guy.
Ha, ha, ha.
What?
It's...
a fine way for parents
to be carrying on.
Hey.
Know what I'd love to do?
What?
Tell Minnie and Roman.
Oh, I know, I know.
It's, uh--
It's, uh, supposed to be
a deep, dark secret,
but I already told them
that we were trying.
They were so pleased.
Tell them.
Back in two minutes?
Mm-hmm.
You're pregnant.
Another blood sample.
Ta-da!
Now, that's what I call good news!
Aw, honey, congratulations.
Thank you.
Best wishes, Rosemary.
Thank you very much.
We are more pleased than we can say.
We didn't have any champagne on hand,
but this will do just as nicely.
When are you due, dear?
June 28th.
Oh, that'll be so exciting.
Listen, dear, you got a good doctor?
Oh, yes, a very good one.
One of the top obstetricians
is a dear friend of
ours, Abe Sapirstein.
Delivers all the society babies.
Abe Sapirstein?
One of the finest obstetricians
in the country.
Wasn't he on Open End
a couple of years ago?
That's right.
Ro?
Uh--
Well, what about Dr. Hill?
Don't worry about Hill.
I'll tell him something.
You know me.
Listen, I won't let you
go to no Dr. Hill
nobody ever heard of.
The best is what you're going
to have, young lady.
Where's your telephone, huh?
It's in the bedroom.
He's a brilliant man.
Very sensitive.
Ro, sit down, sit down.
No, I'm fine.
Abe, Minnie.
Fine.
Listen, Abe, a dear friend of ours
Just found out today she's pregnant.
Yeah, isn't it?
I'm in her apartment right now.
We told her you'd be glad
to take care of her.
You wouldn't charge her none of your
fancy society prices neither.
Well, just wait a minute.
Rosemary, tomorrow morning at 11:00?
All right.
Yeah, 11:00's fine, Abe.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, well, you, too.
No, no, no, no, not at all.
All right.
Well, let's hope so.
Good-bye.
Well, there you are.
Thanks a million, Minnie.
I don't know how to thank
you, both of you.
Just have a fine, healthy
baby, that's all.
My, I can't wait to tell Laura-Louise.
Oh--
Uh, please don't tell anyone
else, not right away.
No, she's right.
There's plenty of time.
Now, to a fine, healthy baby.
Hear, hear.
Hear!
Andy.
Or Susan.
Susan.
Please don't read books.
No pregnancy was ever exactly like
the ones described in the books.
And don't listen to
your friends, either.
No two pregnancies are ever alike.
Dr. Hill prescribed vitamin pills.
No pills.
Minnie Castevet has a herbarium.
I'm going to have her make
a daily drink for you
that'll be fresher, safer,
and more vitamin-rich
than any pills on the market.
Any questions you have,
call me night or day.
Call me, not your Aunt Fanny.
That's what I'm here for.
Here.
What's in it?
Snips and snails and puppy dogs" tails.
That's fine, but what if we
want a girl?
Do you?
It would be nice if the
first one were a boy.
Well, there you are.
No, really, what is
init?
A raw egg, gelatin, herbs.
Tannis root?
Some of that along with
some other things.
Don't be so violent, Harry.
If you want to be stupid,
be nonviolent stupid,
I'm in love with no one.
Especially not your fat wife.
I'm a hopeless cripple--
What's that?
I-I've been to Vidal Sassoon.
Don't tell me you paid for that.
Guy, I have a pain.
Where?
Here.
Just now?
Since Monday.
A sharp pain.
Did you see Sapirstein?
I'm seeing him on Wednesday.
This is ridiculous.
Why don't you see Sapirstein?
Why didn't you say anything?
I see him Wednesday regular.
An entirely natural expansion
of the pelvis.
You can fight it with ordinary aspirin.
I was afraid it might be
an ectopic pregnancy.
Ectopic?
I thought you weren't going
to read books, Rosemary.
It was staring at me in the drugstore.
All it did was worry you.
Will you go home and
throw it away, please?
The pains will be gone in two days.
Ectopic pregnancy.
I look awful.
What are you talking about?
You look great.
It's that haircut that looks awful.
You want the truth, honey,
that's the worst mistake you ever made.
My Goa!
It's Vidal Sassoon.
It's very in.
What's wrong with you?
Do I look that bad?
Terrible!
You're not on one of those
Zen diets, are you?
No.
Then what is it?
Have you seen a doctor?
Hutch, I might as well tell you.
I'm pregnant.
Oh, rubbish.
Pregnant women gain weight.
They don't lose it.
I don't sleep well.
I have stiff joints or something,
so I get a pain.
Nothing serious.
Well, congratulations.
You must be very happy.
Oh, I am.
We both are.
Who's your obstetrician?
Abraham Sapirstein.
Oh! He delivered two of
my daughter's babies.
He's one of the best in the city.
When did you see him last?
Um, yesterday.
And?
And he says it's fairly common.
How much weight have you lost?
Uh, 3 pounds.
Nonsense. You've lost
far more than that.
It's perfectly normal to
lose a little at first.
Later on, I'll be gaining.
Well...
we must assume Dr. Sapirstein
knows whereof he speaks.
He should.
He charges enough.
We're getting bargain rates.
Our neighbors are close friends of his.
Oh?
I'll go.
Stay where you are.
It hurts less when I move around.
Oh, I was just talking about you.
Favorably, I hope.
Do you need anything from outside?
No. Thank you for asking.
Is Guy home already?
He won't be home till 6:00.
Oh.
A friend of ours is here.
Would you--
Would you like to meet him?
If I won't be intruding.
No. Please come in.
Hutch, this is Roman Castevet.
Edward Hutchins.
How do you do?
Oh, how are you, sir?
I was just telling Hutch
that it was you and Minnie
who sent me to Dr. Sapirstein.
Oh, so Rosemary has told
you the good news.
Yes, she has.
We must see that she
gets plenty of rest.
I was a bit alarmed by her appearance.
Well, she has lost some weight,
but that's quite normal
for the early months.
Later on, she'll gain,
probably far too much.
So I gather.
Please sit down.
Mrs. Castevet makes a vitamin
drink for me every day
from fresh herbs she grows.
Yes, all according to Dr. Sapirstein's
directions, of course.
He's inclined to be suspicious
of commercially prepared vitamin pills.
Indeed? But surely they're manufactured
under every imaginable safeguard.
That's quite true, but commercial pills
can sit for months on a druggist's shelf
and lose a great deal of
their original potency.
I hadn't thought of that.
I like the idea of having everything
fresh and natural.
I'll bet expectant mothers
chewed bits of tannis root
when nobody'd even heard
of vitamin pills.
Tannis root?
It's one of the herbs
she puts in the drink.
Oris it an herb?
Can a root be an herb?
You sure you don't mean
anise or orris root?
No, tannis.
Hmm.
Look.
It's good luck, too.
Ish!
Ha.
Doesn't look like, uh, root matter,
more like mold or fungus of some kind.
Is it ever called by any other name?
Not to my knowledge, no.
Tannis. I must look it up
in the encyclopedia.
What a pretty holder or
charm or whatever it is.
The Castevets gave it to me.
You and your wife
seem to be taking better
care of Rosemary
than her own parents.
We're very fond of her.
And of Guy, too.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I'll have to go.
My wife is waiting for me.
It's a pleasure to have met you.
Oh, don't bother, Rosemary.
We'll meet again, I'm sure.
I just noticed he has pierced ears.
Pierced ears and piercing eyes.
What's she like?
Nosy. Funny.
Guy's gotten very close to them.
I suppose they've become sort
of parent figures for him.
And you?
Sometimes I think they're
too friendly and helpful.
Hey, what a surprise.
How are you, Hutch?
Good to see you.
You're the surprise.
What happened?
They stopped for a rewrite,
those dumb bastards.
Ah, stay where you are.
Nobody move.
Would you like some coffee?
Love some.
Loot!
Seems congratulations are in order.
Yeah, it's wonderful, isn't it?
When's the baby due?
June 28th.
Did you know that Dr. Sapirstein
delivered two of Hutch's grandchildren?
Really?
Mmm.
I met your neighbor.
Roman Castevet.
Oh, did you?
Funny old duck, isn't he?
Did you ever notice he has pierced ears?
You're kidding.
No, I'm not. I saw.
It's a shame we haven't
seen more of you lately,
but with me being so busy
and Ro being the way she is,
we really haven't seen anyone.
Perhaps we can have
dinner together soon.
You're not going, are you?
Thanks for the coffee, my dear.
Thank you for coming, my dear.
This isn't mine.
It must be yours.
Right you are.
Have you thought about names,
or is it too soon?
Andrew or Douglas if it's a boy,
Melinda or Sarah if it's a girl.
Sarah?
What happened to Susan?
Say, is there another of these around?
Oh.
I don't see it, Hutch.
No, it's not here.
I probably left it at the city center.
I'll stop back there.
Let's really have that dinner, shall we?
Definitely.
Next week.
Bye.
Bye-bye.
It was a nice surprise.
Guess what he said.
What?
I look terrible.
Good old Hutch.
He's spreading cheer wherever he goes.
I'm going to get a paper, honey.
He's a professional crepehanger.
He's not a professional crepehanger.
Then he's one of the
top-ranking amateurs.
Hello.
Oh, uh, she's not feeling too well.
Well, I think she's asleep.
All right.
Oh, she could be, yeah.
All right, can you hold on a minute?
It's Hutch.
He wants to speak to you.
Oh.
I told him you were resting,
but he said he couldn't wait.
Hutch?
Tell me, dear, do you go out at all?
Well, I-I haven't been going out. Why?
Can you meet me tomorrow
morning at 11:00
in front of the Time-Life building?
Yes, if you want me to.
What is it?
Can't you tell me now?
I'd rather not.
We can have an early lunch if you like.
That would be nice.
Good. 11:00 then?
Okay.
Oh, did you find your glove?
No, they didn't have it.
Good night, Rosemary.
Sleep well.
You, too. Good night.
What was that?
He wants to talk to me.
What about?
I don't know.
He wouldn't say.
I think those boys' adventure
stories are going to his head.
Where are you meeting him?
Uh, Time and Life building
tomorrow at 11:00.
This is ridiculous.
You're pregnant.
I've got the yens.
I'm getting an ice-cream cone.
You want one?
Yeah, I'd love one.
Vanilla?
Okay.
Hi.
Minnie, I'm going out now,
so I won't have my drink at 11:00.
That's fine, dear.
Take it later.
Buzz me when you get back, huh?
Pain, begone.
I will have no more of thee.
Yes?
Is this Edward Hutchins' apartment?
Yes. Who is this, please?
My name is Rosemary Woodhouse.
I had an appointment with Mr. Hutchins.
Is he there?
Hello?
He was taken ill this morning.
Taken ill?
Yes.
He's in a deep coma at
St. Vincent's hospital.
That's awful.
I just spoke to him
last night about 10:30.
I spoke to him at 11:00.
Who is this?
You don't know me, Rosemary.
I'm Grace Cardiff, Hutch's friend.
Um, do they know what's causing it?
No, they don't know yet.
At the moment, he's
totally unresponsive.
Oh, I'm going to the hospital now.
Is there anything I can do?
Not really.
All right, um, thank you.
No!
This is what I call the
long arm of coincidence!
Ho, ho, ho!
I said to myself, as long
as Rosemary's going out,
I might as well go out and do a
little bit of Christmas shopping.
Now here you are.
Here I am.
Isn't that something?
Aw, darling, what's the matter?
You feel all right?
Aw... aw, you poor thing.
You know what I think?
I think we better be going home now.
What do you say?
No, no, you have your shopping to do.
Ah, shoot, there's two more weeks.
It'll stop any day now.
It's like a wire inside me
getting tighter and tighter.
Usually older women with
less flexible joints
have this sort of trouble.
I'm not going out anymore.
You don't have to.
One minute to go!
Rosemary, I want you to meet Dr. Shand.
He used to be a famous dentist.
He made the chain for your charm.
Oh, how do you do?
Come on, sweetie.
Put this wonderful hat on.
Doctor, come over here.
Minnie, Minnie.
Happy new year.
Have a good year.
To 1966!
The year 1!
What the hell are you doing?
Planning the menu.
We're having a party
a week from Saturday.
It's for our old--
I mean, our young friends.
Minnie and Roman are not invited.
Neither is Laura-Louise.
Nor is Dr. Sapirstein.
It's going to be a very special party.
You have to be under 60 to get in.
Well.
For a minute there, I didn't
think I was going to make it.
You'll make it, all right.
You can be bartender.
Oh, swell.
Do you really think it's
such a good idea?
I think it's the best idea
I've had in months.
Don't you think you ought to check
with Dr. Sapirstein first?
What for? I'm just giving a party.
I'm not going to swim
the English Channel.
What about the pain?
Oh, haven't you heard?
It'll go away in a day or two.
That looks interesting.
What's it for?
We're having some people
over on Saturday.
Oh, you feel up to entertaining?
Yes, I do.
These are old friends
I haven't seen in a long time.
They don't even know yet
that I'm pregnant.
I'll give you a hand if you like.
I'll help you dish things out.
No, thank you, Minnie, but I can manage.
It's going to be a buffet,
and we're getting a bartender, so--
I'll help you take the coats.
No, really, you do too
much for me as it is.
Well, let me know if
you change your mind.
Drink your drink now.
I'd rather not.
Not right this minute.
I'll drink it in a little while.
It don't do to let it stand.
No, I won't wait too long.
You go on back,
and I'll bring the glass
back to you later.
I'll wait.
I'll save you the walk.
You'll do no such thing.
It makes me very nervous
when people watch me cook.
Now, scoot.
Don't let it stand too long.
It's going to lose its vitamins.
You dirty, stinking secret-keeper.
Congratulations!
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Hey, Rosie.
Yeah?
Bob and Leo got stuck
at another party, dear,
but they'll be over right away.
Oh, fine.
You're so lucky.
It's a fantastic house.
Hi.
It's been so long.
You look like a piece of chalk.
You make him feed you, love.
Adrian Marcato lived here.
And the Trench sisters.
Trent sisters?
Trench. They ate little children.
He doesn't just mean
they ate them.
He means they ate
them.
I made their first one strong
to get them happy,
then I go light and conserve, eh?
Rosie, do you feel okay?
You look a little tired.
Thanks for the understatement.
How do you like C.C. Hill?
Isn't he a dream boy?
Mm-hmm, but I-I--
I'm not going to him.
You're not?
I've got another doctor named
Sapirstein, an older man.
Oh, congratulations, Papa.
Thanks. Weren't nothing to it.
Ro, I'm going to take that dip inside.
Oh, yeah, please.
See my flowers?
Yeah.
Elise, will you give me a hand?
Oh, yeah, sure.
Hey, whatever happened to the other guy?
Is he still blind?
Donald Baumgart?
Well, you know who he is.
He's the boy that Zoe Piper
lives with.
He's writing a play.
Is he still blind?
Yeah. He's going through hell
trying to make the adjustment.
He dictates, and Zoe writes.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I just had a cramp for a minute.
Don't cry.
It's all right.
It's good for her.
Let her cry it out.
It's all right, darling.
It's all right.
Sit down, sit down.
Hey, let me in.
Sorry, girls only.
I want to talk to Rosemary.
You can't.
She's busy.
I have to wash these--
Use the bathroom.
It hurts so much.
I'm so afraid the baby's gonna die.
When did the pain start?
um...
in, uh, November.
November?
What?
You have been in pain
since November,
and he's not doing anything
to help you?
He says it's gonna stop.
Why don't you go to see another doctor?
No, he's very good.
He was on Open End.
He sounds like a sadistic nut.
Rosemary, pain like that
is a warning that something isn't right.
Go see Dr. Hill.
Go see anybody besides that-- that--
That nut.
You can't go on suffering like this.
I won't have an abortion.
Nobody's telling you
to have an abortion.
Just go to see another
doctor, that's all.
The thing to do now is move.
Guy?
Yeah?
I'm going to Dr. Hill Monday morning.
Dr. Sapirstein is either
lying, or he's--
I don't know, out of his mind.
Pain like this is a warning
something's wrong.
Rosemary--
And I'm not drinking Minnie's
drink anymore.
I want vitamins and pills
like everyone else.
I haven't drunk it for
the last three days.
I've thrown it away.
You've what?
I've made my own drink.
Is that what those bitches
were giving you in there?
And is that their hint for today?
They're my friends--
They're a bunch of not
very bright bitches
who ought to mind their
own goddamn business!
All they said was get a second opinion.
Rosemary, you got the best
doctor in New York.
You know who Dr. Hill is?
He's a charlie nobody.
That's who he is!
I'm tired of hearing how
great Dr. Sapirstein is.
Well, we'll have to pay Sapirstein.
We'll have to pay Hill.
It's out of the question.
No, I'm not changing.
I just wanna go to Dr. Hill
and get a second opinion.
I won't let you do it, Ro.
I mean, because it's, uh--
It's not fair to Sapirstein.
Not fair to--
What are you talking about?
What about what's fair to me?
You want a second opinion?
You tell Sapirstein and let
him decide who gives it.
No! I want Dr. Hill!
At least have that much courtesy--
If you won't pay,
then I'll--
Ro?
Rosemary?
What is it?
It stopped.
What?
The pain stopped just like that.
Stopped?
Stopped.
What was in that drink you made?
uh...
eggs, milk, sug--
Sugar.
What else?
Ha!
Come on, Rosemary, for Christ's sakes,
what else was in that drink?
It's alive!
Guy, it's moving!
It's all right!
Feel. Feel.
Oh, yeah, I felt it.
Don't be scared.
It won't bite you.
It's wonderful.
It really is.
I feel it kicking.
It's alive!
It's moving!
I'll, uh, clean up some of this mess.
Watch the walls.
Thanks, boys.
Have one on the baby.
Thank you very much.
What's that for?
This is my hospital suitcase.
Honey, you got three weeks.
Yes?
Hello, Mrs. Cardiff.
No.
Oh, my God.
Yes, of course I will.
Hutch is dead.
I feel awful.
All this time, I didn't
even think of him.
Doris, we'll see you later.
I beg your pardon.
I'm Mrs. Woodhouse.
I knew your father.
Oh, so you're Rosemary.
I'm terribly sorry.
Thank you.
This is my sister Edna.
How do you do?
And my husband.
I'm sorry to be late.
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'm Grace Cardiff.
I was hoping to meet you.
Thank you for calling me.
I was going to mail this, but then
I thought you would be here.
What is it?
A book.
Hutch regained consciousness
at the end,
and he thought it was the next morning.
You know, when you had the appointment.
Oh, yes.
I wasn't there, but he told the doctor
to make sure you got the
book that was on his desk.
Thank you.
Oh, and I'm to tell you
the name is an anagram.
The name of the book?
Apparently.
He was delirious, so
it's hard to be sure.
I heard you come in.
It certainly wasn't very long.
I was late.
I couldn't get a taxi.
Oh, what a shame.
Oh, you got mail already?
Somebody gave it to me.
Here. I'll hold it.
Book.
Oh, I know that house.
The Gilmores used to live there.
Oh?
Yeah.
I've been there lots of times.
Grace-- That's one of my favorite names.
Yes.
You need anything?
Nothing, thank you.
Take a nap, why don't you?
I'm going to.
Yeah. Good-bye.
"Born in Glasgow in 1846,
he was soon after brought to New York."
"He resided for several
years in the United St--
He was attacked by a mob"
outside the Bram--
Outside, not in the lobby."
There are no witches.
Not really.
The name is an anagram.
Now, that really makes sense.
Poor Hutch.
Ro?
What's with the chain?
What's the matter?
You all right?
I'm fine.
Oh.
Oh, why, thank you.
How was the funeral?
Okay.
Got the shirt that was
in the New Yorker.
I got that shirt that
was in the New Yorker.
That's nice.
Do you know who Roman really is?
What do you mean, honey?
He's Adrian Marcato's son.
What?
Come here.
I want to show you something.
Roman Castevet is Steven
Marcato rearranged.
It's from Hutch.
Look.
And look here.
There he is when he was 13.
See the eyes?
Coincidence.
In the same house?
And look. Look here.
"Soon after that in August, 1886,
his son Steven was born."
1886. Got it?
That makes him 79 now.
No coincidence.
No, I guess not.
He's Steven Marcato, all right.
Poor old geezer.
With a crazy father like that,
no wonder he switched his name around.
You don't think he's the same?
What do you mean, a witch?
Ro, are you kidding?
Oh, Ro, honey.
His father was a martyr to it.
Do you know how he died?
Honey, it's 1966.
This was published in 1933.
There were covens in Europe.
That's what they're called--
the, um, congregation.
Covens in Europe, in America,
and in Australia,
and they have one right
here, that whole bunch.
The parties with the singing and
the flute and the chanting,
those are esbats or Sabbaths
or whatever they're called.
Honey, don't get excited.
Read what they do, Guy.
They use blood in their rituals.
The blood that has the most
power is baby's blood.
And they don't just use the blood,
they use the flesh, too.
Rosemary, for God's sakes!
They're not setting foot in
this apartment ever again.
They're not coming within
50 feet of the baby.
They're old people.
They have a bunch of old friends.
Dr. Shand happens to play the recorder.
I'm not taking any chances
with the baby's safety.
We're gonna sublet and move out.
We are not.
We'll talk about it later.
I don't think you ought
to read any more of that.
Just this last chapter.
Not today, honey.
Look. Your hands are shaking.
Come on.
Give it to me.
Guy!
I mean it, now.
Give it to me.
Fantastic.
Absolutely fantastic.
What'd you say the name was,
Marchado?
Marcato.
He told me his father
was a coffee importer.
He told Guy he was a producer.
I understand how disturbed
you must be
to have him for a close neighbor.
I don't want anything more
to do with him or Minnie.
I can't take even the slightest chance
where the baby's safety's concerned.
Absolutely.
Any mother'd feel the same way.
Is there any chance at all
that maybe Minnie put something
harmful in those drinks
or in those little cakes?
No, Rosemary, I'd have seen
evidence of it long ago.
I won't take anything else
from them.
You won't have to.
I can give you some pills
that'll be adequate
these last few weeks.
In a way, this may be the answer
to Minnie and Roman's problem, too.
What do you mean?
Roman's very ill.
In fact, confidentially, he has
no more than a month or two left.
I had no idea.
He wanted to pay a last visit to
a few of his favorite cities.
They didn't want to offend you
by leaving before the baby's birth.
I'm sorry to hear that Roman isn't well.
He'd be extremely embarrassed
if he knew what you found out.
Suppose we do this.
I'll tell him to leave on Sunday.
I'll say I spoke to you,
and you understand.
Are you sure they'll leave on Sunday?
I'll see to it.
No matter where we are,
our thoughts are gonna
be with you every minute
till you're all happy and thin again,
your sweet little boy or girl
laying safely in your arms.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything.
Yeah. You make Guy send us
lots of pictures, ya hear?
Yes, I will.
Now, I'm not going to
wish you good luck,
because you won't need it.
You're going to have
a happy, happy life.
Have a good trip and come back safely.
Perhaps. But I may stay
in Dubrovnik or Pescara
or maybe Majorca.
We shall see.
Come back.
Bye, Minnie.
Yeah, good-bye.
Good-bye, Roman.
Bye-bye.
Take care now.
Kennedy airport, Pan Am building.
Bye!
Bye, Roman.
Oh, boy.
Guy?
Hmm?
Where's my book?
Oh, I put it in the garbage.
What?
I didn't want you upsetting
yourself anymore.
Guy, Hutch gave me that book.
He left it to me.
I wasn't thinking about that.
That's a terrible thing to do.
I'm sorry. I wasn't
thinking about Hutch.
Hey, watch out, lady!
"In some cults it was believed that
a personal possession of the victim
was necessary and spells cannot be cast"
without one of the victim's belongings."
Yeah?
Is this Donald Baumgart?
That's right.
This is Rosemary Woodhouse,
Guy Woodhouse's wife.
Oh, yes.
I want to know--
You must be a happy little lady,
living in the Bram, rows
of uniformed lackeys.
I wanted to know how you are,
if there's been any improvement.
Well, bless your heart.
Ha, ha, hal
Guy Woodhouse's wife, huh?
Well, I'm splendid.
I only broke six glasses today.
Guy and I are both very unhappy
that he got his break because
of your misfortune.
Aw, what the hell.
That's the way it goes, right?
I'm sorry I didn't come along
that day he came to visit you.
V-Visit?
Oh, you mean the day we met for drinks?
Yes, that's what I meant.
By the way, he has something
of yours, you know.
What do you mean?
Don't you know?
No.
Didn't you miss anything that day?
You don't mean my tie, do you?
Yes.
Oh, well, he's got mine,
and I've got his.
He can have it back.
I'm sorry.
Doesn't matter to me now what
color tie I'm wearing.
I didn't understand.
I thought he'd only borrowed it.
Oh, no.
It was a trade.
Or...
do you think he stole it?
I have to hang up now.
I just wanted to know if there'd
been any improvement.
No, no, there isn't.
It was nice of you to call. Bye.
You aren't in labor, are you?
No, but I have to see the doctor.
It's very important.
But he has to leave at 5:00,
and there is Mrs. Byron.
I'm sure he'll see you.
Just sit down.
Thank you.
How is it out there?
Oh, awful. 94.
Ugh!
See you next week.
Make an appointment.
Yes, I will.
You're due any day now, aren't you?
Tuesday.
You're smart to get it
over with before August.
Mrs. Byron.
He'll see you right after.
Well, let's see, um...
July the 10th?
What time?
4:00?
Fine.
All right.
See you then.
Thank you.
Bye-bye.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Mmm! That smells nice.
What is it?
Oh, my--
It's called Detchema.
Well, it's a big improvement
on your regular,
if you don't mind my saying.
That wasn't a perfume.
That was a good luck charm.
I threw it away.
Good.
Maybe the doctor will
follow your example.
Dr. Sapirstein?
Yes. The aftershave.
But it isn't, is it?
I don't think he has a good luck charm.
Anyway, he has the same
smell once in a while.
When he does--
Oh, boy.
Haven't you ever noticed?
No.
Well, maybe you thought it was
your own you were smelling.
What is it, a chemical thing?
Will you excuse me a moment, please?
My husband is waiting outside.
I have to go and tell him something.
I'll be back in a minute.
Dr. Hill's office.
Dr. Hill, please.
This is his answering service.
Would you like to leave a message?
Um, yes. My name is Rosemary Woodhouse.
Woodhouse.
And would you ask him to call
me back right away, please?
Uh, my number is 475-2598.
It's an emergency.
I'm in a phone booth.
All right.
Quickly, please, Dr. Hill, call me.
Oh, oh, really?
Did he really say that?
Oh, he didn't say that.
What else was it that he said?
Oh, that's wonderful.
That's wonder--
That's marvelous.
Yes. Dr. Hill?
Did I get the name right?
Is it Rosemary Woodhouse?
Yes.
Are you Dr. Hill's patient?
No.
Um, yes, I mean, well,
I've seen him once.
Um, please, please tell him
he has to speak to me.
It's important.
Tell him to call me, hmm?
All right.
Thank you.
All of them.
All in it together.
All of them witches.
Don't you worry, little Andy or Jenny,
I'll kill them before
I let them touch you.
Yes. Dr--
Mrs. Woodhouse?
Yes!
Oh, thank you, thank you for calling me.
Thought you were in California.
No. No, I've been to another doctor,
and he isn't good, Dr. Hill.
He's been lying to me
and giving me unusual kinds
of drinks and capsules.
The baby's due on Tuesday.
Remember you told me June 28th?
Well, I want you to deliver it.
Mrs. Woodhouse--
Please let me talk to you.
Let me come and explain
what's been going on.
I can't stay too long here.
They'll be coming, looking for me.
Dr. Hill?
Dr. Hill, there's a plot--
I know that sounds crazy.
You're probably thinking,
"My God, this poor girl
has really flipped,"
but I haven't flipped,
Dr. Hill, I swear.
By all the saints, I haven't.
There are plots against
people, aren't there?
Yes, I suppose there are.
Well, then there's one
against me and my baby.
Come to my office tomorrow after 5:00.
Now! Right now.
Mrs. Woodhouse, I'm
not at my office now.
I'm home. I've been up
since yesterday morning.
I beg you.
I can't stay here.
My office at 8:00.
Yes, thank you.
Oh, wait! Dr. Hill?
Yes?
My husband may call you, asking--
I'm not gonna speak to anyone.
I'm gonna take a nap.
Thank you.
Keep the change.
Uh, driver, please,
could you wait and watch until--
Until I'm inside the door?
He lied to you.
He said we were going to Hollywood.
The worst thing of all, he's
involved with them as well.
He sleeps in pajamas now.
He never used to before.
He's probably hiding a mark.
You know they give you
marks when you join--
All sorts of rituals.
They hold Sabbaths there.
You could hear them singing
through the wall.
Guy, my husband Guy said
it was Dr. Shand,
one of these people playing a recorder.
Now, how did he know it was Dr. Shand
unless he was there with them?
Um, they're very clever people.
They planned everything
right from the beginning.
They probably made some
sort of deal with Guy.
They gave him success, and
he promised them our baby
to use in their rituals.
I know this sounds crazy,
but I've-- I've got books here. Look.
There was another actor like
him, Donald Baumgart,
and they put a spell on him.
They cast a spell on him
and made him blind
so that Guy could get his part.
Look, here.
I had this friend Edward Hutchins.
Maybe you heard of him, a writer.
He wrote stories for boys.
Anyway, he was my good friend
since I first came to New York.
May I keep this?
Yes, please, and, look, anyway,
once Mr. Hutchins came to visit me--
Came to visit me.
It was the time I was having
this pain, Doctor.
I was suffering so--
You can't imagine how
much I was suffering,
and they wouldn't help me. Nobody would.
They were giving me a drink
with tannis root in it.
Also witches' stuff, tannis root.
Hutch came, and he immediately
saw something was wrong.
He-- He knew about witches, you see.
Suddenly, Guy rushed in
with his makeup still on,
which he never did.
They probably called him to come home
and steal one of Hutch's belongings,
which he did.
Took his glove,
and they put a spell on him, too.
Put him in a coma.
Three months later, he died.
Now, maybe all of this is coincidence,
but one thing is for sure.
They have a coven, and
they want my baby.
Certainly seems that way.
I was afraid you wouldn't believe me.
I don't believe in witchcraft,
but there are plenty of maniacs
and crazy people in this city.
The doctor's name is Shand, you say?
N-No, Dr. Shand is one of these people.
The doctor's name is Sapirstein.
Abraham Sapirstein?
Yeah.
Do you know him?
I've met him once or twice.
To look at him, you'd never think he--
No, you wouldn't.
Not in a million years.
Would you like to go into
Mount Sinai right now,
this evening?
Yeah, I would love to.
Would that be possible?
It's difficult, but we'll try.
I want you to lie down
and get some rest.
Thanks.
Anything they've got, even
a broom closet'd be fine.
I hope we can do better than that.
I'll see what I can do,
then I'll check you over.
Oh, should I undress now?
No. It'll take me about a half
an hour on the telephone.
You just lie down, rest.
Okay?
Okay.
God bless Dr. Hill.
Everything's going to be
okay, now, Andy or Jenny.
We're going to be in
a nice, clean hospital
with no visitors.
Oh.
Monsters.
Unspeakable.
I was sleeping.
Come with us quietly, Rosemary.
Don't argue or make a scene
because if you say anything more
about witches or witchcraft,
we're going to be forced to take
you to a mental hospital.
You don't want that, do you?
So put your shoes on.
We just want to take you home.
No one's going to hurt you.
Or the baby.
Put your shoes on.
She's fine now.
We're going to go home and rest.
That's all it takes.
Thank you for your trouble, Doctor.
Glad I could be of help, sir.
It's a shame you had to
come in here.
Good evening, Mrs. Woodhouse.
Mrs. Woodhouse!
Uhh!
Ro!
Ro! Ro!
Ro, baby, Ro!
Ro!
Come on, open up, Ro.
Go to hell!
Come on, honey.
No one's going to hurt you.
You promised them the baby, get out!
No, I didn't promise them anything.
What are you talking about?
Promised who?
Rosemary, you're--
Hello.
Elise.
Mrs. Dunstan is out.
Who is this?
The babysitter.
Do you know where she went?
They went to the movies.
This is Rosemary.
Please ask her to call Rosemary
the second she gets home.
It's terribly urgent. Don't--
Don't forget.
Don't worry.
I'll tell her.
Thank you.
We don't want to hurt you, Ro.
We're your friends, Rosemary.
There's nothing to be
afraid of, Rosemary.
Honest and truly there isn't.
This is nothing but a mild
sedative to calm you down.
You know I wouldn't let any--
Ro.
Aah!
Ro, Ro!
Help me!
Oh, Ro, baby.
Somebody, help me!
Aah!
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute now.
We happen to be in labor here.
Here?
Here.
You're all right, baby.
You're gonna be perfectly all right.
I swear to God you will.
There were supposed to
be doctors, hospitals!
Doctors, hospitals!
Everything-- Everything's
clean and sterile!
No, she isn't here, Elise.
I'll have her call you back.
Oh, Andy...
Andy or Jenny...
I-I'm sorry, my little darling.
Forgive me!
Hi.
Is it all right?
Yes, it's fine.
What is it?
A boy.
Really? A boy.
And it's all right?
Yes.
Where is it?
Ohh! Oh, my goodness.
Oh, gee, what a start you
gave me. My goodness.
The baby, where is it?
Oh, uh, you wait here one minute.
Where's my baby?
Uh, I'll go find Dr. Abe.
Ju-Just wait.
Where's the baby?
Where is it?
Honey--
There were complications,
Rosemary,
but nothing that will
affect future births.
It's--
Dead.
It was in the wrong position.
In the hospital I might have been
able to do something about it,
but you wouldn't listen.
Honey, we can have others
as soon as you're better.
I promise you.
Absolutely.
You can start on another
in a very few months.
As soon as you're better.
No.
I don't believe you.
You're both lying.
You're lying!
It didn't die!
You took it!
You're lying!
You're witches!
You're lying! You're lying!
You're lying!
Abe says it's called prepartum.
I don't know.
It's some kind of a hysteria.
Boy, you were really kapow,
out of your mind.
Uh, I know where you got the idea
that Minnie and Roman were witches,
but, um, how come you thought that
Abe and I joined the party?
Um, let's face it, darling.
You had the prepartum crazies.
Now you're going to rest, and
you're going to get over them.
I know this is the worst thing
that ever happened to you,
but from now on, everything's
going to be roses.
Paramount's within an inch
of where we want them,
and suddenly Universal's
interested, too,
and we're going to blow this town,
and we're going to be in the
beautiful hills of Beverly
with a pool, a spice garden,
the whole schmeer,
and the kids, too, Ro.
Scout's honor.
You heard what Abe said.
Now, I got to run now and get famous.
Let me see your shoulder.
Are you kidding?
Your left shoulder.
All right.
Anything you say.
I generally prefer doing this to music.
Left shoulder.
Right shoulder.
And that's as far as I go
without a blue light.
The high pressure area that we see here
has been causing this extreme
heat and humidity.
And unfortunately will be staying
with us city dwellers
through the rest of the week.
It will be hot and overcast
upstate New York as well
with the possibility of thunder
showers tonight and tomorrow
with gradual clearing by tomorrow night.
All you people leaving the city this
upcoming weekend should find it hot.
Do you hear a baby crying?
Why, no, I don't, dear.
Now, you come and get into your bed now.
It's time for you to take your pill.
Did you turn the air conditioner off?
Mm-hmm.
Well, you mustn't do that, dear.
Why, people are actually
dying, it's so hot.
What do you do with the milk?
Why, uh, throw it away.
Your pill, Rosemary.
Hello, girls.
Whew. 95 out.
Some new people moved on in up in 8.
Do they have a baby?
How'd you know that?
I heard it crying.
Oh, wait a minute.
Oh, no.
Don't do that.
Why not?
Uh, a little messy, that's all.
Easy, easy.
Got her too high.
Not if he's still waiting
for a plane, he isn't.
Oh, hell, now, Hayato.
You're just making fun of me.
You're pulling my leg, like we say.
Aah!
Rosemary, go back to bed.
You know you're not supposed
to be up and around.
Is the mother?
Uh, Rosemary--
Shut up.
You're in Dubrovnik.
I don't hear you.
What have you done to it?
What have you done to its eyes?
He has his father's eyes.
What are you talking about?
Guy's eyes are normal.
What have you done to him,
you maniacs?
Satan is his father, not Guy.
He came up from hell and begat
a son of mortal woman.
Hail, Satan!
Satan is his father, and
his name is Adrian.
He shall overthrow the mighty
and lay waste their temples.
He shall redeem the despised
and wreak vengeance
in the name of the burned
and the tortured!
Hail, Adrian!
Hail, Satan!
He chose you out of all the world.
Out of all the women in the
whole world, he chose you.
He arranged things because he wanted you
to be the mother of his only living son.
His power is stronger than stronger!
His might shall last longer than longer!
Hail, Satan!
No!
It can't be!
Go look at his hands.
And his feet.
Oh, God!
God is dead!
Satan lives!
The year is one!
Hail, Satan!
The year is one, and God is done!
Oh, God!
The year is one!
Hail, Adrian!
Hail, Satan!
Why don't you help us out,
Rosemary?
Be a real mother to Adrian.
You don't have to join
if you don't want to.
Just be a mother to your baby.
Minnie and Laura-Louise are too old.
It's not right.
Think about it, Rosemary.
Oh, God!
Oh, shut up with your "Oh, Gods,"
or we'll kill you, milk or no milk.
You shut up.
Rosemary's his mother, so
you show some respect.
Come, my friend.
Come see him.
Come see the child.
What would you like to drink?
They, uh, promised me
you wouldn't be hurt,
and you haven't been, really.
I mean, supposing you had
the baby, and you lost it.
Wouldn't that be the same?
And we're getting so much
in return, Ro.
Oh, Guy, let me introduce you
to Argyron Stavropoulos.
How proud you must be.
Is this the mother?
Why in the name of--
Here, drink this.
You'll feel a little better.
What's in it?
Tannis root?
Nothing's in it.
Just plain, ordinary Lipton's
tea. You drink it.
Get away from here.
Roman.
You're rocking him too fast.
Sit down. Get her out of here.
Put her where she belongs.
You're rocking him too fast.
That's why he's crying.
Oh, mind your own business.
Let Rosemary rock him.
Go on, sit down with the others.
Well, she's liable to--
Sit down with the others,
Laura-Louise.
Rock him.
You're trying to get me
to be his mother.
Aren't you his mother?